<set id="w19_deen" source-language="de" target-language="en">
  <seg id="1" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.sl">
    <source>Erdoğan eröffnet Moschee in Köln</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.ref">Erdoğan opens mosque in Cologne</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.ht">Erdoğan opens mosque in Cologne</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.mt">Erdoğan opens mosque in Cologne</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="2" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.sl">
    <source>Der türkische Präsident Recep Tayyip Erdoğan hat am Samstag die Ditib-Moschee in Köln offiziell eröffnet.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.ref">The Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdoğan officially opened the Ditib mosque in Cologne on Saturday.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.ht">Turkish president Recep Tayyip Erdoğan officially opened the Ditib mosque in Cologne on Saturday.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.mt">Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdoğan officially opened the Ditib Mosque in Cologne on Saturday.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="3" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.sl">
    <source>Erdoğan hatte sich zuvor bei seinem dreitägigen Staatsbesuch unter anderem mit Kanzlerin Angela Merkel und Bundespräsident Frank-Walter Steinmeier getroffen.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.ref">During his three-day state visit, Erdoğan met with Chancellor Angela Merkel and Federal President Frank-Walter Steinmeier.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.ht">Previously in his three-day visit, Erdoğan attended meetings with Chancellor Merkel and President Steinmeier.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.mt">Erdoğan had previously met German Chancellor Angela Merkel and German President Frank-Walter Steinmeier, among others, during his three-day state visit.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="4" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.sl">
    <source>Kritik an Deutschland</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.ref">Criticism of Germany</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.ht">Criticism of Germany</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.mt">Criticism of Germany</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="5" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.sl">
    <source>In seiner Eröffnungsrede forderte Erdoğan die deutsche Regierung dazu auf, in Deutschland lebende Anhänger der Gülen-Bewegung auszuliefern und gegen kurdische Separatisten vorzugehen.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.ref">In his opening speech, Erdoğan called on the German government to extradite adherents of the Gülen movement living in Germany and to take action against Kurdish separatists.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.ht">In his speech, Erdoğan demanded that the German government extradite followers of the Gülen movement and take action against Kurdish separatists.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.mt">In his opening speech, Erdoğan called on the German government to extradite Gülen supporters living in Germany and to take action against Kurdish separatists.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="6" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.sl">
    <source>Wir werden unsere Bürger schützten - egal, wo sie leben.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.ref">We will protect our citizens wherever they live.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.ht">We will protect our citizens, no matter where they live.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.mt">We will protect our citizens, no matter where they live.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="7" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.sl">
    <source>Wir werden nicht zulassen, dass Sympathisanten der PKK oder Gülen-Bewegung unsere Bürger erschüttern und der deutsch-türkischen Freundschaft schaden", sagte er.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.ref">We will not allow sympathizers of the PKK or Gülen movement to unsettle our citizens and damage the German/Turkish friendship’, he said.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.ht">We will not allow PKK or Gülen sympathizers to cause our citizens unrest and damage the German-Turkish friendship", he said.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.mt">We will not allow sympathizers of the PKK or Gülen movement to upset our citizens and harm German-Turkish friendship, "he said.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="8" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.sl">
    <source>Für die Eröffnung der Ditib-Moschee war die Kölner Innenstadt teilweise gesperrt worden.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.ref">Inner city Cologne was partially blocked for the opening of the Ditib mosque.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.ht">Parts of Cologne city center were cordoned off for the opening of the mosque.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.mt">The city centre of Cologne was partially closed for the opening of the Ditib Mosque.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="9" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.sl">
    <source>Mehrere tausend Polizisten waren im Einsatz - unter ihnen auch Scharfschützen.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.ref">Many thousands of police were deployed, including snipers.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.ht">Thousands of police officers were on duty - some in riot gear.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.mt">Several thousand police officers were deployed - including snipers.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="10" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.sl">
    <source>Der Islamverband Ditib steht in der Kritik, weil er als verlängerter Arm der türkischen Regierung gilt.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.ref">The Ditib Islamic association is under criticism because it is seen as an extended arm of the Turkish government.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.ht">The Ditib Islamic association has been criticized as a front organization of the Turkish government.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_011_euronews-de.135557.mt">The Islamic association Ditib is under criticism because it is seen as an extension of the Turkish government.</translation>
  </seg>
</set>
