<set id="w19_deen" source-language="de" target-language="en">
  <seg id="1" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.sl">
    <source>Auslands-Ticker: Zahl der Toten auf Sulawesi steigt auf mehr als 400</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ref">International news ticker: Number of dead in Sulawesi rises to more than 400</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ht">International News: Number of dead on Sulawesi rises to more than 400</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.mt">Foreign ticker: Death toll in Sulawesi rises to more than 400</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="2" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.sl">
    <source>Nach dem schweren Erdbeben der Stärke 7,5 und anschließenden Tsunami auf der indonesischen Insel Sulawesi ist von mindestens 420 Todesopfer die Rede.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ref">After the severe magnitude 7.5 earthquake and subsequent tsunami on the Indonesian island of Sulawesi, there are reports of at least 420 casualties.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ht">At least 420 people are reported to have died after a severe earthquake measuring 7.5 on the Richter scale followed by a tsunami on the Indonesian island of Sulawesi.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.mt">At least 420 people have been reported dead following the powerful 7.5-magnitude earthquake and subsequent tsunami on the Indonesian island of Sulawesi.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="3" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.sl">
    <source>Die Opferzahl könne noch weiter steigen.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ref">Reportedly, the number of victims could rise even further.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ht">The number of victims could yet rise further.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.mt">The death toll could rise further, he said.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="4" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.sl">
    <source>Die Rettungsmannschaften sind noch nicht in die verwüsteten und von der Außenwelt abgeschnittenen Gebiete vorgedrungen.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ref">The rescue teams have not yet progressed into the ravaged and isolated areas.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ht">Rescue teams have not yet been able to move into the desert region, which is cut off from the outside world.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.mt">Rescue teams have not yet entered the devastated areas cut off from the outside world.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="5" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.sl">
    <source>Elon Musk tritt als Tesla-Aufsichtsratschef zurück</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ref">Elon Musk resigns as Tesla chairman</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ht">Elon Musk resigns as head of Tesla</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.mt">Elon Musk resigns as Tesla chief executive</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="6" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.sl">
    <source>Am Anfang war ein Tweet.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ref">In the beginning, there was a tweet.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ht">It all started with a tweet.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.mt">In the beginning was a tweet.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="7" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.sl">
    <source>Tesla-Chef Elon Musk sorgte Anfang August für Unruhe an den Aktienmärkten, als er einen Rückzug des Eletroautobauers ankündigte.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ref">Tesla boss Elon Musk caused nervousness on the stock markets in early August when he announced a withdrawal by the electric car manufacturer.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ht">Tesla chief Elon Musk caused uncertainty on the equity markets when he announced that he would step down as head of the electric car manufacturer.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.mt">Tesla boss Elon Musk caused a stir in the stock markets in early August when he announced the electric car maker was pulling out.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="8" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.sl">
    <source>Die US-Börsenaufsicht verklagte ihn wegen Betrugs, doch jetzt haben sich beide geeinigt.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ref">The US Securities and Exchange Commission sued him for fraud, but the parties have now agreed to a settlement.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ht">The SEC had accused him of fraud; both parties have reached a settlement.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.mt">The US Securities and Exchange Commission sued him for fraud, but the two have now reached an agreement.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="9" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.sl">
    <source>Tesla und Musk müssen zahlen, und der Tesla-Chef zieht sich aus dem Aufsichtsrat zurück, Vorstandsvorsitzender darf er aber bleiben.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ref">Tesla and Musk have to pay, and the Tesla boss steps down as chairman, but he may remain as CEO.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ht">Tesla and Musk have to pay a fine, and the Tesla chief will step down from the supervisory board, however, he will be able to remain CEO.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.mt">Tesla and Musk will have to pay, and the Tesla chief executive will step down from the board, but he will be allowed to remain chief executive.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="10" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.sl">
    <source>Parteitag der britischen Konservativen</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ref">The British Conservative Party Conference</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ht">British Conservative party conference</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.mt">British Conservative Party Conference</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="11" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.sl">
    <source>Scharf bewacht - der Parteitag der Tories</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ref">Under tight security - the Tory party conference</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ht">Closely guarded - the Tory party conference</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.mt">Tightly guarded - the Tory party conference</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="12" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.sl">
    <source>Birmingham wird zur Bühne eines Machtkampfes.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ref">Birmingham becomes the stage for a power struggle.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ht">Birmingham become the stage of a power struggle.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.mt">Birmingham is becoming the stage for a power struggle.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="13" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.sl">
    <source>Auf dem Parteitag soll es um Außenpolitik, Handelsfragen und Entwicklungspolitik gehen, doch überschattet wird die viertägige Konferenz von dem Streit zwischen Premierministerin Theresa May und den Brexit-Hardlinern, an vorderster Front Ex-Außenminister Boris Johnson.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ref">The party conference was to address foreign policy, trade issues and development policy, but the four-day conference was overshadowed by the conflict between Prime Minister, Theresa May and the Brexit hardliners, with ex-Foreign Minister, Boris Johnson in the frontline.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ht">The main topics on the agenda are foreign policy, trade issues and development policy, but the four-day conference is being overshadowed by the dispute between Prime Minister Theresa May and Brexit hardliners, headed by ex-Foreign Secretary Boris Johnson.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.mt">The party conference is expected to focus on foreign policy, trade and development, but the four-day conference will be overshadowed by the row between Prime Minister Theresa May and Brexit hardliners, led by ex-Foreign Secretary Boris Johnson.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="14" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.sl">
    <source>Referendum für einen neuen Staatsnamen</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ref">Referendum for a new state name</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ht">Referendum on new country name</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.mt">Referendum for a new state name</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="15" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.sl">
    <source>Die Außenminister Mazedoniens (rechts) und Griechenlands haben sich schon geeinigt</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ref">The foreign ministers of Macedonia (right) and Greece have reached agreement</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ht">The foreign ministers of Macedonia (right) and Greece have come to an agreement</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.mt">The foreign ministers of Macedonia (right) and Greece have already reached an agreement</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="16" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.sl">
    <source>Mazedonien ist ein Staat auf dem Balkan, Mazedonien ist aber auch eine Provinz in Nord-Griechenland.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ref">Macedonia is a state in the Balkans, but Macedonia is also a province in Northern Greece.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ht">Macedonia is the name of a state in the Balkans, Macedonia is also the name of a province in northern Greece.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.mt">Macedonia is a state in the Balkans, but Macedonia is also a province in northern Greece.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="17" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.sl">
    <source>Skopje und Athen streiten über diese Namensdopplungen schon seit Jahren.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ref">Skopje and Athens have been arguing about the duplicate name for years.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ht">Skopje and Athens have been in dispute over the name issue for years.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.mt">Skopje and Athens have been arguing over these duplications of names for years.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="18" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.sl">
    <source>Jetzt haben sie sich geeinigt.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ref">Now they have come to an agreement.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ht">Now they have come to an agreement.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.mt">Now they have agreed.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="19" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.sl">
    <source>Der Staat Mazedonien soll künftig Nord-Mazedonien heißen und darüber stimmt an diesem Sonntag die Bevölkerung ab - ob es gut geht?</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ref">In future, the state of Macedonia is to be called North Macedonia and the population will vote on this measure on Sunday from the population - will it turn out okay?</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ht">From now on, the state of Macedonia will be called North Macedonia and this Sunday, Macedonians will go to the polls to vote on the name change. Whether this will be the end of the issue remains to be seen.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.mt">The state of Macedonia is to be called Northern Macedonia in the future, and the population will vote on it this Sunday - will it be all right?</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="20" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.sl">
    <source>Proteste in Brasilien gegen Rechtspopulisten Bolsonaro.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ref">Protests in Brazil against right-wing populist Bolsonaro.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ht">Protests in Brazil against right-wing populist Bolsonaro.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.mt">Protests in Brazil against right-wing populist Bolsonaro.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="21" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.sl">
    <source>"Ele Nao" ("Der nicht") - gemeint ist Jair Bolsonaro.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ref">Ele Nao ("Not him") - addressed to Jair Bolsonaro.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ht">"Ele Nao" ("Not Him") - the man in question is Jair Bolsonaro.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.mt">"Ele Nao" ("The Not") - meaning Jair Bolsonaro.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="22" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.sl">
    <source>Eine Woche vor der Präsidentschaftswahl in Brasilien ist die Stimmung im Land gespalten.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ref">One week before the presidential election in Brazil and the mood in the country is divided.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ht">One week before the presidential election in Brazil, the mood is split.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.mt">A week before Brazil's presidential election, the mood in the country is divided.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="23" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.sl">
    <source>Tausende gingen in mehreren Städten auf die Straße, um gegen den Rechtspopulisten Jair Bolsonaro zu protestieren.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ref">In many cities thousands are taking to the street to protest against the right-wing populist Jair Bolsonaro.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ht">Thousands marched in the streets across several cities to protests against the right-wing populist Jair Bolsonaro.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.mt">Thousands took to the streets in several cities to protest against right-wing populist Jair Bolsonaro.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="24" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.sl">
    <source>Der "Trump Brasiliens" gibt sich als Anti-System-Kandidat und liegt damit in den Umfragen vorne.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ref">The ‘Brazilian Trump’ is presenting himself as an anti-system candidate and is ahead in the polls.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ht">The "Brazilian Trump" has presented himself as an anti-establishment candidate and is currently ahead in the polls.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.mt">The "Trump of Brazil" presents himself as an anti-system candidate and is thus ahead in the polls.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="25" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.sl">
    <source>Sein schärfster Konkurrent ist Fernando Haddad von der Linken Arbeiterpartei.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ref">His keenest competitor is Fernando Haddad from the left workers’ party.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.ht">His closest rival is Fernando Haddad of the left-wing Worker's Party.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_006_dw.82618.mt">His closest rival is Fernando Haddad of the left-wing Workers' Party.</translation>
  </seg>
</set>
