<set id="w19_deen" source-language="de" target-language="en">
  <seg id="1" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.sl">
    <source>"Global Citizen Festival": Musik gegen Armut: Stars, Buhrufe und Schrecksekunde</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ref">Global Citizen Festival: Music against poverty: Stars, boos and scary moments</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ht">"Global Citizen Festival": music against poverty: stars, boos and scary moments</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.mt">"Global Citizen Festival": Music against poverty: Stars, boos and moments of horror</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="2" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.sl">
    <source>Musiker wie Janet Jackson, John Legend, Shawn Mendes und Cardi B haben bei einem gemeinsamen Konzert im New Yorker Central Park für mehr Engagement im Kampf gegen Armut und Krankheiten geworben.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ref">Musicians such as Janet Jackson, John Legend, Shawn Mendes and Cardi B campaigned for more engagement in the fight against poverty and illness at a collective concert in New York’s Central Park.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ht">Musicians including Janet Jackson, John Legend, Shawn Mendes and Cardi B have called for more action against poverty and disease in a concert in New York's Central Park.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.mt">Musicians including Janet Jackson, John Legend, Shawn Mendes and Cardi B have called for more engagement in the fight against poverty and disease at a joint concert in New York's Central Park.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="3" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.sl">
    <source>"Engagiert Euch, wo auch immer ihr nur könnt", sagte Mendes bei dem Festival in der Nacht zum Sonntag vor rund 60.0000 Zuschauern.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ref">Get involved wherever you can, said Mendes on Sunday evening at the festival in front of approximately 60,000 spectators.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ht">"Get involved, wherever you can", said Mendes to a festival crowd of around 60,000 on Sunday night.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.mt">"Get involved wherever you can," Mendes said at the festival on Sunday night in front of a crowd of about 60,000.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="4" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.sl">
    <source>Danke, dass Ihr hierher gekommen seid, das ist ein Traum.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ref">Thank you for coming, this is a dream.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ht">Thank you for coming here, it is a dream come true.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.mt">Thank you for coming here, this is a dream.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="5" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.sl">
    <source>Cardi B trat in einem roten Outfit mit Fransen und goldenem Mikrofon auf.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ref">Cardi B appeared in a red outfit with tassels and a gold microphone.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ht">Cardi B appeared in a red outfit with tassels and a golden microphone.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.mt">Cardi B performed in a red outfit with fringe and a gold microphone.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="6" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.sl">
    <source>Ich bin nervös, ich schwitze, aber es ist okay, denn ich bin hier und bereit, die Welt zu verändern.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ref">I am nervous, I am sweating, but it’s OK because I’m here and ready to change the world.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ht">I am nervous, I'm sweating, but it is okay, because I am here and I am ready to change the world.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.mt">I'm nervous, I'm sweating, but it's okay because I'm here and ready to change the world.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="7" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.sl">
    <source>Auch Schauspieler wie Hugh Jackman und Forest Whitaker sowie Vertreter von Regierungen, den Vereinten Nationen und Hilfsorganisationen zeigten sich bei dem mehrstündigen Spektakel auf der Bühne.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ref">Even actors such as Hugh Jackman and Forest Whitaker, government representatives, the United Nations and aid organizations appeared on the stage at the spectacle, which lasted for hours.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ht">Actors such as Hugh Jackman and Forest Whitaker as well as representatives from governments, the UN and aid organizations appeared on stage at the festival, which ran for several hours.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.mt">Actors including Hugh Jackman and Forest Whitaker, as well as representatives of governments, the United Nations and aid agencies, also took to the stage for the several-hour spectacle.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="8" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.sl">
    <source>Zwischendurch gab es allerdings eine Schrecksekunde, als viele Zuschauer das Geräusch einer umfallenden Metallabsperrung für Schüsse hielten, Angst bekamen und versuchten zu fliehen.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ref">There was a scary moment when many spectators mistook the noise of a falling metal barrier for shots, got scared and tried to run away.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ht">During the concert, there was a moment of fear when many concertgoers, mistaking the noise of a falling metal barrier for gunfire shots, took fright and tried to flee.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.mt">In between, however, there was a moment of terror, when many spectators mistook the sound of a falling metal barrier for shots, became frightened and tried to flee.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="9" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.sl">
    <source>Kurz entstand Panik, Menschen rannten durcheinander.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ref">There was a short panic with people running in all directions.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ht">There was a brief moment of panic as people ran about.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.mt">Briefly there was panic, people were running around in confusion.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="10" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.sl">
    <source>Sieben Zuschauer seien dabei leicht verletzt worden, sagte der Veranstalter Hugh Evans.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ref">Seven spectators were slightly injured, said organizer Hugh Evans.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ht">Organizer Hugh Evans said that seven people were injured in the confusion.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.mt">Seven spectators were slightly injured in the incident, organiser Hugh Evans said.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="11" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.sl">
    <source>Die New Yorker Polizei und der Musiker Chris Martin beruhigten die Menschen dann jedoch von der Bühne aus.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ref">The New York police and musician Chris Martin calmed the audience from the stage.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ht">New York police and musician Chris Martin took to the stage to calm the spectators.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.mt">However, New York police and musician Chris Martin then calmed people down from the stage.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="12" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.sl">
    <source>"Niemand versucht, irgendjemanden zu verletzen", sagte Martin.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ref">Nobody is trying to injure anyone, said Martin.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ht">"Nobody is trying to hurt anyone", said Martin.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.mt">"No one is trying to hurt anyone," Martin said.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="13" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.sl">
    <source>Ihr seid alle in Sicherheit.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ref">You are all safe.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ht">You are all safe here.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.mt">You are all safe.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="14" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.sl">
    <source>Tickets für das "Global Citizen Festival"-Konzert gab es wie jedes Jahr kostenlos im Internet.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ref">As every year, tickets for the "Global Citizen Festival" concert were available free of charge online.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ht">Tickets for the "Global Citizen Festival" concert were - as they are every year - free of charge.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.mt">As every year, tickets for the "Global Citizen Festival" concert were available free of charge on the Internet.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="15" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.sl">
    <source>Wer eines ergattern wollte, musste im Internet Texte, Fotos und Videos über den globalen Kampf gegen Armut und Krankheiten lesen und weiterverbreiten.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ref">If you wanted to get one, you had to read and share texts, photos and videos about the global fight against poverty and diseases online.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ht">Those wishing to get one had to read and share texts, videos and photos on the global fight against poverty and disease.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.mt">If you wanted to get one, you had to read and distribute texts, photos and videos about the global fight against poverty and disease on the Internet.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="16" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.sl">
    <source>Für die zahlreichen Musiker und Schauspieler gab es vom Publikum Jubel und Applaus - Buhrufe dagegen für den republikanischen Senator Jeff Flake.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ref">For the numerous musicians and actors there were cheers and applause from the audience - by contrast, Republican Senator Jeff Flake was booed.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ht">There were cheers and applause from the audience for the various musicians and actors - but there were boos for Republican senator Jeff Flake.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.mt">There were cheers and applause from the audience for the numerous musicians and actors - but boos for Republican Senator Jeff Flake.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="17" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.sl">
    <source>Dieser sprach sich zwar gemeinsam mit seinem demokratischen Kollegen Chris Coons auf der Bühne für mehr Gleichberechtigung von Männern und Frauen aus.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ref">Flake did join his Democratic colleague Chris Coons on the stage in calling for more equal rights between men and women.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ht">Flake, together with his Democrat colleague Chris Coons, declared support for gender equality.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.mt">He did, however, join fellow Democrat Chris Coons on stage to speak out for more equality between men and women.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="18" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.sl">
    <source>Am Freitag hatte sich Flake aber im Justizausschuss des US-Senats für die Nominierung von Brett Kavanaugh als Richter am Supreme Court ausgesprochen und damit viele Frauen vor den Kopf gestoßen.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ref">On Friday, however, Flake had spoken in the Judiciary Committee of the US Senate supporting the nomination of Brett Kavanaugh as a judge on the Supreme Court, which offended many women.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ht">On Friday, however, Flake supported the nomination of Brett Kavanaugh as Supreme Court judge in the Senate Justice Committee, offending many women in the process.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.mt">But on Friday, Flake spoke out in favor of Brett Kavanaugh's nomination as a Supreme Court justice in the US Senate Judiciary Committee, alienating many women.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="19" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.sl">
    <source>Mindestens drei Frauen haben Missbrauchsvorwürfe bis hin zur versuchten Vergewaltigung gegen Kavanaugh erhoben, die dieser zurückweist.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ref">At least three women made abuse allegations, including some of attempted rape against Kavanaugh, who rejects these.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ht">At least three women have made allegations ranging from sexual assault to rape against Kavanaugh, which he denies.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.mt">At least three women have made allegations of abuse, including attempted rape, against Kavanaugh, which he denies.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="20" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.sl">
    <source>Flake forderte eine FBI-Untersuchung der Vorwürfe, nachdem ihn zwei Frauen, die eigenen Angaben zufolge selbst sexuelle Übergriffe erlebt haben, auf dem Weg zur Ausschusssitzung in einem Aufzug konfrontierten.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ref">Flake called for an FBI investigation after two women who reportedly experienced sexual assault themselves confronted him on the way to a committee meeting in an elevator.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ht">Flake demanded an FBI investigation into the claims after the two women, who claim to have experienced sexual assault themselves, confronted him in a lift when he was on his way to a committee session.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.mt">Flake called for an FBI investigation into the allegations after two women who say they themselves experienced sexual assault confronted him in an elevator on the way to the committee meeting.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="21" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.sl">
    <source>"Ihr könnt auch gerne jederzeit in einem Aufzug mit mir zusammenkommen", sagte Flake nun bei dem Konzert in New York zur Zuschauermenge.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ref">You are welcome to join me in an elevator anytime, Flake said to the crowd at the New York concert.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.ht">"You are more than welcome to take the lift with me any time", Flake said to the crowd of spectators at the New York concert.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_012_dzonline.de.180384.mt">"You're welcome to join me in an elevator any time," Flake told the crowd at the concert in New York.</translation>
  </seg>
</set>
