<set id="w19_deen" source-language="de" target-language="en">
  <seg id="1" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_002_an-online.de.383344.sl">
    <source>DFB-Chef Grindel sieht keine Grundlage für Özil-Comeback</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_002_an-online.de.383344.ref">The president of DFB Grindel sees no basis for the returning of Özil</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_002_an-online.de.383344.ht">DFB head Grindel sees no reason for Özil comeback</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_002_an-online.de.383344.mt">DFB chief Grindel sees no basis for Özil comeback</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="2" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_002_an-online.de.383344.sl">
    <source>Berlin DFB-Präsident Reinhard Grindel sieht derzeit keine Grundlage für eine Rückkehr von Mesut Özil in die Nationalmannschaft.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_002_an-online.de.383344.ref">Berlin - The president of DFB Reinhard Grindel sees no basis for the returning of Mesut Özil to the national team.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_002_an-online.de.383344.ht">Berlin - DFB President Reinhard Grindel currently sees no return to the national side for Mesut Özil.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_002_an-online.de.383344.mt">Berlin DFB president Reinhard Grindel currently sees no basis for Mesut Özil's return to the national team.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="3" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_002_an-online.de.383344.sl">
    <source>"Das ist eine Frage, die natürlich davon abhängt, dass man einmal ins Gespräch kommt, dass man mit ihm auch darüber spricht, warum er das eine oder andere offenbar so empfunden hat, wie das in seinem Statement niedergelegt ist", sagte Grindel im Fußball-Podcast "Phrasenmäher" der "Bild-Zeitung.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_002_an-online.de.383344.ref">There is an open question so you get into a conversation, you talk to him about why you have apparently felt that way, how is stated in his statement, said Grindel in football Podcast "Phrasenmäher" of the newspaper "Bild-Zeitung".</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_002_an-online.de.383344.ht">"This is not just a question of being talked about at any particular time, of why he appears to have experienced one thing or the other in the ways he has described in his statement", said Grindel on the Bild-Zeitung "Phrasenmäher" football podcast.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_002_an-online.de.383344.mt">"This is a question that of course depends on the fact that you get into a conversation, that you also talk to him about why he obviously felt one way or the other, as stated in his statement," Grindel said in the football podcast "Phrasenmower" of the "Bild-Zeitung.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="4" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_002_an-online.de.383344.sl">
    <source>Trotz der nun monatelangen Debatte um die Fotos von Özil mit dem türkischen Präsidenten Recep Tayyip Erdogan bedauere er den Rücktritt des 92-fachen Nationalspielers Özil.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_002_an-online.de.383344.ref">In spite of the debate going on for months about the photos of Özil with the Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan, he regrets the return of the 92-match national player Özil.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_002_an-online.de.383344.ht">In spite of the debate surrounding Özil posing for pictures with Turkish president Recep Tayyip Erdogan, which has dragged on for several months, Grindel regrets the decision of Özil, who has 92 caps, to retire from international football.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_002_an-online.de.383344.mt">Despite months of debate over Özil's photos with Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan, he said he regretted the resignation of the 92-time international Özil.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="5" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_002_an-online.de.383344.sl">
    <source>"Ich hätte mich gefreut, wenn Mesut Özil weiter für Deutschland gespielt hätte.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_002_an-online.de.383344.ref">I would be happy if Mesut Özil continued to play for Germany.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_002_an-online.de.383344.ht">"I would have been happy if Mesut had continued to play for Germany.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_002_an-online.de.383344.mt">"I would have been happy if Mesut Özil had continued to play for Germany.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="6" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_002_an-online.de.383344.sl">
    <source>Ich bin auch bis zu einem gewissen Zeitpunkt davon ausgegangen, dass das so sein würde", sagte Grindel.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_002_an-online.de.383344.ref">At some point of time I also assumed that it will happen, said Grindel.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_002_an-online.de.383344.ht">Up to a certain point in time, I still believed that he would", said Grindel.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_002_an-online.de.383344.mt">I also assumed up to a point that this would be the case, "Grindel said.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="7" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_002_an-online.de.383344.sl">
    <source>De 29-Jährige hatte im Juli seinen Rücktritt aus dem DFB-Team erklärt und diesen auch damit begründet, dass ihn Grindel nicht gegen rassistische Anfeindungen während der WM verteidigt habe.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_002_an-online.de.383344.ref">The 29-year-old had declared that he quits DFB team in July and explained it with the fact that Grindel did not protect him against racist hostility during the World Cup.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_002_an-online.de.383344.ht">The 29 year-old announced his retirement from international football in July and, in justifying his decision, said that Grindel did not defend him against racial abuse during the World Cup.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_002_an-online.de.383344.mt">The 29-year-old had announced his retirement from the DFB team in July, citing the fact that Grindel had not defended him against racist hostility during the World Cup.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="8" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_002_an-online.de.383344.sl">
    <source>Der DFB-Chef wiederholte seine Kritik an Özil, dass dieser nicht für ein Gespräch mit Bundestrainer Joachim Löw und Teammanager Oliver Bierhoff bereit sei.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_002_an-online.de.383344.ref">The DFB head repeated his criticism of Özil and that he is not ready for a discussion with national coach and team manager Oliver Bierhoff.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_002_an-online.de.383344.ht">The DFB head repeated his criticism of Özil for refusing to hold discussions with head coach Joachim Löw and general manager Oliver Bierhoff.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_002_an-online.de.383344.mt">The DFB chief repeated his criticism of Özil for not being ready for a conversation with national coach Joachim Löw and team manager Oliver Bierhoff.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="9" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_002_an-online.de.383344.sl">
    <source>Er habe keinen Druck aufbauen wollen, aber er kenne es aus dem Fußball so, dass wenn "man eine Mannschaft verlässt oder einen Verein wechselt, dass man darüber mit seinem Trainer spricht und ich es schade finde, dass dieses Gespräch bisher nicht zustande gekommen ist".</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_002_an-online.de.383344.ref">He did not want to create any pressure, but he knows that in football ‘if you leave a team or change club, you talk to your trainer and I think it is sad that this discussion did not happen before’.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_002_an-online.de.383344.ht">He did not want to put anyone under pressure, but he knows that, in football, "when someone leaves a team or switches clubs, they discuss it with their manager and I think it is a shame this discussion did not take place earlier".</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_002_an-online.de.383344.mt">He said he didn't want to build pressure, but he knows from football that when "you leave a team or change a club, you talk about it with your coach and I think it's a shame that that conversation hasn't come to fruition."</translation>
  </seg>
</set>
