<set id="w19_deen" source-language="de" target-language="en">
  <seg id="1" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.sl">
    <source>Pressefreiheit: Bundesregierung verteidigt Rauswurf des Journalisten</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.ref">Freedom of Press: Federal government defends exclusion of journalist</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.ht">Press Freedom: Federal Government Defends Expulsion of Journalist</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.mt">Press freedom: Federal Government defends expulsion of journalist</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="2" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.sl">
    <source>Regierungssprecher Steffen Seibert hat den Rauswurf eines Journalisten von der Pressekonferenz von Kanzlerin Angela Merkel (CDU) und dem türkischen Präsidenten Recep Tayyip Erdoğan verteidigt.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.ref">Government spokesperson Steffen Seibert has defended the expulsion of a journalist from the press conference of Chancellor Angela Merkel (CDU) and Turkish president Recep Tayyip Erdoğan.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.ht">Government spokesperson Steffen Seibert has defended the expulsion of a journalist from the press conference of Chancellor Angela Merkel and Turkish President Recep Erdoğan.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.mt">Government spokesman Steffen Seibert has defended the expulsion of a journalist from the press conference of Chancellor Angela Merkel (CDU) and Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdoğan.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="3" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.sl">
    <source>Im Kanzleramt hatte der in Hamburg lebende türkische Journalist ein T-Shirt mit der türkischen und deutschen Aufschrift "Freiheit für Journalisten" übergezogen und war in die erste Reihe gegangen.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.ref">In the chancellery, the Turkish journalist living in Hamburg had put on a T-shirt with the Turkish and German writing “Freedom for journalists” and was sitting in the first row.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.ht">In the chancellery, the Turkish journalist, who now lives in Hamburg, put on a t-shirt that read in both Turkish and German "Freedom for Journalists" and then went into the front row.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.mt">In the Chancellery, the Turkish journalist, who lives in Hamburg, had put on a T-shirt with the Turkish and German words "Freedom for Journalists" and had gone to the front row.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="4" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.sl">
    <source>Das T-Shirt, sei nicht das Problem gewesen, sagte Seibert der Bild am Sonntag.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.ref">The T-shirt was not the problem, Seibert said to the Bild on Sunday.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.ht">The t-shirt was not the problem Seibert told the Bild am Sonntag weekly newspaper.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.mt">The T-shirt was not the problem, Seibert told Bild am Sonntag.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="5" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.sl">
    <source>Es ging um eine Störung des Ablaufs der Pressekonferenz.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.ref">It was about a disruption in the course of the press conference.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.ht">It was instead because of disturbing the press conference.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.mt">It was about disrupting the flow of the press conference.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="6" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.sl">
    <source>Durch die Aktion des Journalisten sei eine starke Unruhe entstanden, was nicht hinnehmbar sei.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.ref">The journalist’s action created a lot of unrest, which was unacceptable.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.ht">The journalist's behavior resulted in massive agitation, which was entirely unacceptable.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.mt">The journalist's action had caused a great deal of unrest, which was unacceptable.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="7" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.sl">
    <source>Er habe deswegen veranlasst, dass Personenschützer den Mann hinausbringen.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.ref">Thus, he ordered bodyguards to escort the man out.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.ht">He therefore prompted the removal of the journalist by the man's own personal bodyguard.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.mt">He said he had arranged for security guards to take the man out.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="8" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.sl">
    <source>Seibert sagte, dass es nicht gestattet sei, bei Pressekonferenzen im Bundeskanzleramt politische Anliegen zu demonstrieren.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.ref">Seibert said that it was not permitted to demonstrate political concerns at press conferences in the federal chancellery.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.ht">Seibert said political demonstrations during press conferences at the chancellery were not allowed.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.mt">Seibert said that it is not permitted to demonstrate political concerns at press conferences in the Federal Chancellery.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="9" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.sl">
    <source>Das gilt völlig unabhängig davon, ob es sich um ein berechtigtes Anliegen handelt oder nicht.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.ref">no matter if it is a legitimate concern or not.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.ht">It is completely immaterial whether the protest has to do with a legitimate concern or not.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.mt">This applies regardless of whether it is a legitimate concern or not.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="10" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.sl">
    <source>Die Regeln sind die Regeln.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.ref">The rules are the rules.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.ht">Rules are rules.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.mt">The rules are the rules.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="11" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.sl">
    <source>In der Türkei sitzen zahlreiche Journalisten im Gefängnis.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.ref">In Turkey, many journalists are imprisoned.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.ht">Numerous journalists are imprisoned in Turkey.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.mt">In Turkey, many journalists are in prison.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="12" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.sl">
    <source>Vielen von ihnen werden angebliche Spionagetätigkeiten oder die Unterstützung oder Mitgliedschaft in verbotenen Parteien oder der Fethullah-Gülen-Bewegung vorgeworfen.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.ref">Many of them are accused of alleged espionage or supporting or being members of prohibited parties or the Fethullah Gülen movement.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.ht">Many of them are accused of allegedly spying or supporting either outlawed political parties or the Fethullah Gülen movement.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.mt">Many of them are accused of alleged espionage activities or support or membership in banned parties or the Fethullah Gülen movement.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="13" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.sl">
    <source>Die türkische Führung macht die Bewegung für den gescheiterten Putschversuch am 15. Juli 2016 verantwortlich.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.ref">The Turkish government holds the movement responsible for the failed attempted coup on July 15, 2016.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.ht">The Turkish government holds the movement responsible for the failed attempted putsch on July 15th, 2016.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.mt">The Turkish leadership blames the movement for the failed coup attempt on July 15, 2016.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="14" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.sl">
    <source>Einigen der beschuldigten Journalisten drohen mehrere Jahrzehnte Haft.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.ref">Some of the accused journalists are facing several decades in jail.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.ht">Some of the convicted journalists are facing many decades of imprisonment.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.mt">Some of the accused journalists face several decades in prison.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="15" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.sl">
    <source>Auch ausländische Journalisten sind vor den türkischen Behörden nicht sicher: Erst Anfang September wurde der österreichische Journalist Max Zirngast verhaftet.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.ref">Even foreign journalists are not safe from Turkish authorities: At the beginning of September, the Austrian journalist Max Zirngast was arrested.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.ht">Foreign journalists are also not safe from the Turkish authorities: at the beginning of September, the Austrian journalist Max Zirngast was imprisoned.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.mt">Foreign journalists are also not safe from the Turkish authorities: Austrian journalist Max Zirngast was only arrested at the beginning of September.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="16" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.sl">
    <source>Zuletzt hatten die Fälle der inhaftierten Journalisten Meşale Tolu und Deniz Yücel für Aufsehen gesorgt.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.ref">Most recently, the cases of the incarcerated journalists Meşale Tolu and Deniz Yücel caused a stir.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.ht">Most recently, the cases of the imprisoned journalists Meşale Tolu and Deniz Yücel have attracted attention.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.mt">Most recently, the cases of the imprisoned journalists Meşale Tolu and Deniz Yücel caused a stir.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="17" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.sl">
    <source>Sie kamen zwar frei und konnten nach Deutschland zurückkehren, doch laufen in der Türkei noch Prozesse gegen die beiden.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.ref">They were released and were able to return to Germany, but the legal processes in Turkey against the two are still ongoing.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.ht">Indeed they were set free and were allowed to return to Germany, despite the fact that neither of their cases has been fully resolved.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_013_zeit.52892.mt">They were released and were able to return to Germany, but the two are still being tried in Turkey.</translation>
  </seg>
</set>
