<set id="w19_deen" source-language="de" target-language="en">
  <seg id="1" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.sl">
    <source>Betriebswerk Pressig war Heimat der Schubloks</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ref">The Pressig depotwas home to the thrust locomotives</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ht">Pressig depot was home to the heavy goods locomotive</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.mt">Pressig depot was the home of the push-pull engines</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="2" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.sl">
    <source>Das Bahnbetriebswerk in Pressig war jahrzehntelang die Drehscheibe im Frankenwald.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ref">For decades the depot in Pressig was the hub of the Franconian Forest.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ht">The Pressig rail depot was the hub of the Franconian forest for decades.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.mt">For decades, the railway depot in Pressig was the hub in the Franconian Forest.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="3" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.sl">
    <source>1991 endete ein Stück Eisenbahn-Historie.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ref">1991 put an end to a piece of railway history.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ht">1991 saw the end of a piece of railway history.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.mt">A piece of railway history ended in 1991.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="4" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.sl">
    <source>"Wenn Puffer an Puffer knallten, hörte man es in ganz Pressig", erinnert sich Georg Dinkel, der die Geschichte des Ortes und des Bahnhofs archiviert.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ref">The crashing from bumper to bumper could be heard throughout Pressig, remembers Georg Dinkel, who archives the history of the place and the stations.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ht">"You could hear the sound of buffers coming together all over Pressig", reminisced Georg Dinkel, who is archiving the history of the town and the railway station.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.mt">"When buffers popped against buffers, you could hear it all over Pressig," recalls Georg Dinkel, who archives the history of the place and the railway station.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="5" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.sl">
    <source>Das regte niemanden auf.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ref">This did not bother anybody.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ht">Nobody was annoyed by the sound.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.mt">No one was upset by that.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="6" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.sl">
    <source>Da quietschten auch die Bremsen und knatterten die Waggons.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ref">The squeaking of brakes and rattling of carriages could also be heard.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ht">The brakes screeched and the wagons rattled.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.mt">Then the brakes squealed and the wagons rattled.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="7" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.sl">
    <source>Das war eben Eisenbahn pur.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ref">This was pure railway.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ht">It was a pure railway sound experience.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.mt">That was just pure railway.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="8" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.sl">
    <source>Aussagen, die sinnbildlich für Dinkels Heimat Pressig stehen.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ref">Statements that are symbolic for Dinkel’s Pressig homeland.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ht">These statements sum up Dinkel's home town of Pressig.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.mt">Statements that are emblematic of Dinkel's homeland Pressig.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="9" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.sl">
    <source>Nirgendwo im Frankenwald wurde ein Ort so durch die Eisenbahn geprägt.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ref">Nowhere in the Franconian forest has a place been characterized by the railway so much.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ht">Nowhere in the Franconian forest has been so deeply influenced by the railways.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.mt">Nowhere in the Franconian Forest has a place been so shaped by the railway.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="10" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.sl">
    <source>Hier war der Ausgangspunkt der Steilrampen-Bergstrecke nach Norden, die nach einem Anstieg um etwa 220 Höhenmeter ihren Scheitelpunkt in Steinbach am Wald hat.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ref">This was the starting point for the steep mountain section to the north, which peaks in Steinbach am Wald following an ascension of about 220 meters.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ht">It was the starting point for the steep mountain route to the north, which reaches its peak in Steinbach am Wals at about 220 meters above sea level.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.mt">This was the starting point of the steep ramp mountain route to the north, which has its apex in Steinbach am Wald after an ascent of about 220 metres in altitude.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="11" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.sl">
    <source>Um das zu bewältigen, wurden früher Zug- und Schubloks benötigt, die in Pressig ihre Heimat hatten.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ref">Previously trains and locomotives housed in Pressig were needed to handle this.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ht">To climb to this peak, heavy goods locomotives were required, which had their home in Pressig.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.mt">In order to cope with this, train and drawer locomotives used to be needed, which had their home in Pressig.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="12" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.sl">
    <source>1901 genehmigte der bayerische Landtag den Bau einer Bahnbetriebswerkstätte mit 21 Lokschuppen, Lehrlingswerkstätte, Fahrleitungs- und Bahnmeisterei.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ref">In 1901 the Bavarian parliament approved the building of a depot with 21 locomotives, apprentice workshops, catenary and railroad maintenance division.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ht">In 1901, the Bavarian state parliament approved the construction of a railway repair workshop with 21 engine sheds, an apprentice workshop and an overhead line and railway maintenance depots.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.mt">In 1901, the Bavarian state parliament approved the construction of a railway workshop with 21 locomotive sheds, apprentice workshop, catenary and railway maintenance.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="13" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.sl">
    <source>"Herzstück war die Drehscheibe, die nach einem Umbau 1899 einen Durchmesser von 18 Metern hatte", erzählt Norbert Heidrich aus Hirschaid, Bahnhistoriker und 47 Jahre lang Berufseisenbahner.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ref">The centerpiece was the turntable, which after reconstruction in the year 1899 had a diameter of 18 metres, says Norbert Heidrich from Hirschaid, a railway historian and a professional railroader with 47 years of experience.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ht">"At the heart of everything was the turntable, which, after conversion work in 1899, had a diameter of 18 meters", explains Norbert Heidrich from Hirschaid, railway historian and 47 year-long railway worker.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.mt">"The centrepiece was the turntable, which, after a conversion in 1899, had a diameter of 18 metres," says Norbert Heidrich from Hirschaid, a railway historian and professional railway worker for 47 years.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="14" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.sl">
    <source>Vom Bahnbetriebswerk (BW) Pressig, das 1968 Bamberg unterstellt wurde, wurden auch Loks für die Nebenstrecken Pressig - Tettau, Ludwigsstadt - Lehesten, Stockheim - Sonneberg und Kronach - Nordhalben betrieben.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ref">The Pressig depot, which in the year 1968 was relocated to Bamberg, also operated locomotives for the branch lines Pressig - Tettau, Ludwigsstadt - Lehesten, Stockheim - Sonneberg and Kronach - Nordhalben.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ht">From the Pressig railway workshop, brought under the control of Bamberg in 1968, locomotives ran on the local routes from Pressig to Tettau, Ludwigsstadt to Lehesten, Stockheim to Sonneberg and Kronach to Nordhalben.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.mt">The railway depot (BW) Pressig, which was subordinated to Bamberg in 1968, also operated locomotives for the branch lines Pressig - Tettau, Ludwigsstadt - Lehesten, Stockheim - Sonneberg and Kronach - Nordhalben.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="15" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.sl">
    <source>Am 15. Juli 1950 berichtete das "Volksblatt" von einem Personalbestand von 160 Mann; 13 Dampf- und acht Elloks waren damals in Pressig stationiert.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ref">On July 15 1950 the "Volksblatt" reported of a staff of 160 men; 13 steam locomotives and eight electric locomotives were stationed in Pressig at that time.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ht">On 15th July 1950, the "Volksblatt" news reported that the workshop had a staff of 160 men; at the time, 13 steam locomotives and 8 electric locomotives were stationed at Pressig.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.mt">On 15 July 1950, the "Volksblatt" reported a staff of 160; 13 steam and eight electric locomotives were stationed in Pressig at that time.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="16" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.sl">
    <source>Die Elektrifizierung der Strecke 1939 minimierte bereits den Bedarf an Zug- und Schubloks.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ref">The electrification of the track in 1939 reduced the need for pulling trains and locomotives.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ht">The electrification of the route in 1939 minimized the need for heavy goods locomotives.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.mt">The electrification of the line in 1939 already minimised the need for train and push locomotives.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="17" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.sl">
    <source>Ab 1977 wurden sie nur noch bei Güterzügen gebraucht.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ref">From 1977 they were still used with freight trains.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ht">From 1977, they were only used for freight.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.mt">From 1977, they were only used for freight trains.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="18" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.sl">
    <source>Bis 1991 wurden im Monat noch mindestens 10 000 Wägen rangiert.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ref">By 1991 at least 10,000 wagons were shunted.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ht">As recently as 1991, at least 10 000 wagons were shunted per month.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.mt">Until 1991, at least 10 000 wagons were still manoeuvred per month.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="19" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.sl">
    <source>1982 wurden Teile des Betriebswerks, 1991 der Rest abgebrochen.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ref">In 1982 the depot was partially dismantled and the remainder in the year 1991.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ht">In 1982, part of the workshop was demolished, with the rest demolished in 1991.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.mt">Parts of the plant were demolished in 1982 and the rest in 1991.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="20" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.sl">
    <source>Heidrich: "Es ist bedauerlich, dass man nicht eine bessere Nutzung des Standortes, auch in puncto Güterverkehr, ins Auge gefasst hat".</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ref">Heidrich: ‘It’s a shame that better use of the location is not envisaged, also with regard to freight traffic’.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ht">Heidrich: "It is a shame that nobody thought of a better use of the location, even as regards freight transport".</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.mt">Heidrich: "It is regrettable that a better use of the site has not been envisaged, including in terms of freight transport."</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="21" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.sl">
    <source>Noch an Pfingsten 1989 feierte die Bahndirektion Nürnberg zum Jubiläum "50 Jahre Elektrifizierung Nürnberg - Saalfeld" ein pompöses Bahnhofsfest in Pressig.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ref">Still in the year 1989 at Pentecost, the Nuremberg Railway Directorate celebrated "50 years of electrification Nuremberg - Saalfeld" with a pompous station festival for the anniversary in Pressig.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ht">On Pentecost in 1989, Nuremberg railway chiefs organised a grand celebration in Pressig to mark "50 years of electrification between Nuremberg - Saalfeld".</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.mt">On Whitsun 1989, the Nuremberg Railway Directorate celebrated the anniversary of "50 years of electrification Nuremberg - Saalfeld" with a pompous station party in Pressig.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="22" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.sl">
    <source>"Da waren 10 000 begeisterte Zuschauer hier", erinnert sich Georg Dinkel.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ref">10,000 enthusiastic spectators were here, remembers Georg Dinkel.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ht">"There was a crowd of 10,000 here", remembers Georg Dinkel.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.mt">"There were 10,000 enthusiastic spectators here," remembers Georg Dinkel.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="23" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.sl">
    <source>Wenig später das Aus.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ref">Shortly afterwards.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ht">Shortly afterwards, it was all over.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.mt">A short time later, the end.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="24" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.sl">
    <source>Am 1. Juni 1991 wurden die letzten 30 Mann abgezogen, der Rangierbahnhof Pressig war Geschichte.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ref">On June 1, 1991 the last 30 men were withdrawn and the Pressig marshalling yard was history.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ht">On 1st June 1991, the last 30 men were laid off and the Pressig shunting yard was history.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.mt">On 1 June 1991, the last 30 men were withdrawn, the Pressig marshalling yard was history.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="25" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.sl">
    <source>"Die Rangierer und Hemmschuhleger erledigten die schwierigsten Arbeiten im Zugverkehr", erinnert Dinkel.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ref">The shunters and wheel scotches took care of the heaviest rail traffic work, remembers Dinkel.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ht">"The shunters and brake fitters did the hardest jobs in transport", remembers Dinkel.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.mt">"The shunting and shoe-laying workers did the most difficult work in train traffic," Dinkel recalls.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="26" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.sl">
    <source>Jeder Fehlgriff hätte fatale Folgen gehabt.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ref">Each mistake could have fatal consequences.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ht">Every mistake could have fatal consequences.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.mt">Any misstep would have had fatal consequences.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="27" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.sl">
    <source>Warum der Bahnhof Pressig-Rothenkirchen für die Umkehr der Hierarchie der beiden Orte geführt hat und viele weitere historische und aktuelle Bilder gibt es hier im infrankenPlus-Artikel.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ref">Why the Pressig-Rothenkirchen station led to a change in the hierarchy of both locations and how many more historical and current pictures there are, is included here in the infrankenPlus article.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.ht">In this infrankenPlus article, find out how the Pressig-Rothenkirchen station transformed the hierarchy of the two towns and see pictures from past and present.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_019_infranken.de.241797.mt">Why the station Pressig-Rothenkirchen led to the reversal of the hierarchy of the two places and many other historical and current pictures can be found here in the infrankenPlus article.</translation>
  </seg>
</set>
