<set id="w19_deen" source-language="de" target-language="en">
  <seg id="1" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.sl">
    <source>Grindel strebt Wiederwahl an - Lahm soll ins DFB-Präsidium</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.ref">Grindel seeking re-election - Lahm to join the Presidential Board of the German football association (DFB)</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.ht">Grindel running for re-election - Lahm to join DFB board</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.mt">Grindel seeks re-election - Lahm to join DFB executive committee</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="2" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.sl">
    <source>Mainz (dpa) - Reinhard Grindel will trotz der Kritik an seiner Person nach dem WM-Aus und der Özil-Affäre im kommenden Jahr erneut für das Amt als DFB-Präsident kandidieren.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.ref">Mainz (dpa) - Despite the criticism directed at him personally following the early FIFA World Cup exit and the scandal around Mesut Özil, Reinhard Grindel wants to run for office as President of the DFB again in the coming year.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.ht">Mainz (dpa) - In spite of the criticism coming his way after Germany's elimination from the World Cup and the Özil saga, Reinhard Grindel wishes to run again for the office of DFB president.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.mt">Mainz (AP) - Reinhard Grindel wants to run for president of the German Football Association (DFB) again next year, despite criticism of him following the World Cup exit and the Özil affair.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="3" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.sl">
    <source>"Ich mache meine Arbeit und bemühe mich, sie so gut zu machen, wie es geht", sagte Grindel als Gast am frühen Sonntagmorgen im "Aktuellen Sportstudio" des ZDF.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.ref">I do my work and try to make it as good as it gets, said Grindel as a guest early Sunday morning on ZDF’s weekly sports broadcast "Das aktuelle Sportstudio".</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.ht">"I am doing my job and I aim to do it to the best standard possible", said Grindel as a guest on ZDF's "Aktuellen Sportstudio" on Sunday morning.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.mt">"I'm doing my job and trying to do it as well as I can," Grindel said as a guest on ZDF's "Current Sports Studio" early Sunday morning.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="4" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.sl">
    <source>Man muss sich ja immer wieder um eine Wiederwahl bemühen, das werde ich tun.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.ref">A re-election should be attempted and that is what I will do.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.ht">Running for re-election is part of the job, and that is what I intend to do.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.mt">You have to keep trying to get re-elected, and I will do that.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="5" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.sl">
    <source>Und dann muss man mal gucken, ob die Unterstützung dann auch da ist.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.ref">And then you have to see what kind of support you get.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.ht">And a candidate has to see whether the support is there.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.mt">And then you have to see if the support is there.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="6" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.sl">
    <source>Der Verbandschef fände es nach eigenen Worten "merkwürdig", wenn er nach dem Zuschlag für die Fußball-EM 2024 nicht "Lust hätte, an dem Zukunftsprojekt mitzuarbeiten".</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.ref">In his own words, the head of the association would find it "strange" if he did not "feel like working on the future project" after Germany was awarded the UEFA European Football Championship 2024.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.ht">In his own words, the association chief would, after securing the hosting of Euro 2024, find it "remarkable" not to "be working on the future project".</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.mt">The FA chief executive said it would be 'strange' if he did not 'feel like working on the project for the future' following the bid for Euro 2024.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="7" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.sl">
    <source>Grindel ist seit April 2016 Verbandschef als Nachfolger des über die Sommermärchen-Affäre gestürzten Wolfgang Niersbach.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.ref">Since April 2016, Grindel has been the head of the association as successor to Wolfgang Niersbach, who had to resign amidst the scandals surrounding the 2006 FIFA World Cup in Germany.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.ht">Grindel has been association chief since April 2016, succeeding Wolfgang Niersbach after the latter resigned amid bribery allegations surrounding the awarding of the 2006 World Cup.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.mt">Grindel has been the head of the association since April 2016, succeeding Wolfgang Niersbach, who was ousted over the summer fairy tale affair.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="8" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.sl">
    <source>Im Herbst 2016 wurde er für eine erste komplette Amtszeit von drei Jahren gewählt.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.ref">In autumn 2016 he was elected for a first full term of three years.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.ht">He was elected for his first full term of three years in autumn 2016.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.mt">In autumn 2016, he was elected for a first full three-year term.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="9" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.sl">
    <source>Die nächste Abstimmung steht beim DFB-Bundestag am 27. September 2019 an.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.ref">The next vote will be held at the DFB’s national conference on September 27, 2019.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.ht">The next vote will be held in the DFB Bundestag on 27 September 2019.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.mt">The next vote is due at the DFB Bundestag on 27 September 2019.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="10" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.sl">
    <source>Der künftige EM-Cheforganisator Philipp Lahm soll laut Grindel im DFB-Präsidium mitarbeiten.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.ref">According to Grindel, the future head organizer of the 2024 European Football Championship in Germany, Philipp Lahm, is to join the DFB Presidential Board.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.ht">According to Grindel, future Euros organizer Philipp Lahm will be a DFB board member.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.mt">According to Grindel, the future head organiser of the European Championships, Philipp Lahm, is to work on the DFB executive committee.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="11" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.sl">
    <source>"Ich würde mich freuen, wenn meine Kollegen im Präsidium einverstanden sind, dass er in dieser Rolle auch zukünftig im Präsidium mit berät und dann natürlich herzlich eingeladen ist, bei sportlichen Fragen seine Erfahrung zur Verfügung zu stellen", sagte Grindel.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.ref">I would be pleased if my colleagues on the presidential board agreed that he will continue to provide advice on the board in this role and then of course we very much invite him to share his experience in sporting matters, said Grindel.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.ht">"I would be delighted if my colleagues on the DFB board agreed that he should, in the future, give advice on the board in this role and is invited to contribute his know-how in sporting matters", said Grindel.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.mt">"I would be pleased if my colleagues in the Bureau would agree that he should continue to advise in this role in the Bureau and then, of course, be cordially invited to make his experience available in sporting matters," Grindel said.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="12" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.sl">
    <source>An Spekulationen, ob Lahm sein Nachfolger als DFB-Chef werden könnte, wollte er sich nicht beteiligen.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.ref">At the same time, he did not want to speculate as to whether or not Lahm could succeed him as head of the DFB.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.ht">He refrained from commenting on speculation that Lahm could succeed him as DFB head.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.mt">He did not want to take part in speculation as to whether Lahm could be his successor as DFB boss.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="13" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.sl">
    <source>Als Konsequenz aus der Affäre um die Fotos von Mesut Özil und Ilkay Gündogan mit dem türkischen Staatspräsidenten Recep Tayyip Erdogan äußerte Grindel den Wunsch, dass künftig ein Nationalspieler ohne Migrationshintergrund Integrationsbotschafter des DFB werden solle.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.ref">As a consequence of the scandal over the photos taken by Mesut Özil and Ilkay Gündogan with the Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan, Grindel expressed a preference for a national team player without an immigration background to fill the position of DFB ambassador for integration.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.ht">As a result of the saga surrounding the photos of Mesut Özil and Ilkay Gündogan with Turkish president Recep Tayyip Erdogan,  Grindel expressed his wish for a national player of a non-migrant background to be made a DFB integration ambassador.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.mt">As a consequence of the affair over the photos of Mesut Özil and Ilkay Gündogan with Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan, Grindel expressed the wish that in the future an international without a migration background should become an integration ambassador of the DFB.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="14" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.sl">
    <source>Derzeit üben dieses Amt der gebürtige Brasilianer Cacau und Celia Sasic aus, letztere hat familiäre Wurzeln in Kamerun.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.ref">Currently, this position is filled by native Brazilian Cacau and Celia Sasic, who traces her family back to Cameroon.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.ht">Currently, this post is held by the native Brazilian Cacau and Celia Sasic, who originates from Cameroon.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.mt">Currently, this position is held by Brazilian-born Cacau and Celia Sasic, the latter with family roots in Cameroon.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="15" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.sl">
    <source>"Wenn da einer ohne Migrationshintergrund deutlich in die Gesellschaft und den Fußball hineinwirkt und sagt, "das Thema ist wichtig, da müssen wir uns kümmern", das wäre auch eine Initiative, um für eine bessere Grundlage zu sorgen für unsere Vereine vor Ort, wo Integration funktionieren muss", sagte Grindel.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.ref">If somebody without a migration background is an obvious influencer in society and football and says, ‘the issue is an important one, we need to do something about it’, ‘this would also be an initiative to provide a better foundation for our local teams, where integration needs to work’, Grindel said.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.ht">"If someone from a non-migrant background makes an impact in football and society and says "this is an important issue, we have to do something about it", this would be an initiative to give us a better basis for our clubs on the ground, where integration counts", said Grindel.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_008_gelnhaeuser-tageblatt.de.204589.mt">"If someone without a migrant background has a clear impact on society and football and says," the issue is important, we have to take care of it, "that would also be an initiative to provide a better basis for our clubs on the ground, where integration has to work," Grindel said.</translation>
  </seg>
</set>
