<set id="w19_deen" source-language="de" target-language="en">
  <seg id="1" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.sl">
    <source>Musik-Contest im Kulturbahnhof: Die "Kö von Hiltrup" und der See</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ref">Music contest at the culture train station: The "Kö von Hiltrup" and the sea</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ht">Music Contest in Kulturbahnhof: the "Kö von Hiltrup" and the Lake</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.mt">Music contest at the Kulturbahnhof: The "Kö von Hiltrup" and the lake</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="2" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.sl">
    <source>Der erste Aufruf zum Musikcontest war ein Erfolg, kreativ und im Miteinander.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ref">The first call to participate in the music contest was a success, creative and cooperative.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ht">The first call for a music contest was a success for creative reasons and to bring people together.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.mt">The first call for the music contest was a success, creatively and in cooperation.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="3" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.sl">
    <source>" D ein Lied für Hiltrup" darzubieten, lautet der Appell der Stadtteiloffensive Hiltrup, im "Musikcontest für große und kleine, junge und erfahrene Musiker".</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ref">Your Song for Hiltrup is the motto of the Hiltrup initiative for the "Music Contest for young and old, new and experienced musicians."</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ht">Reading "Your Song for Hiltrup" the appeal from Hiltrup's neighborhood campaign reached out for a "music contest for big and small, as well as experienced and inexperienced musicians".</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.mt">"D is a song for Hiltrup," is the appeal of the district offensive Hiltrup, in the "music contest for big and small, young and experienced musicians."</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="4" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.sl">
    <source>Ein Contest "mit Augenzwinkern in der sympathischen Hiltruper Familie", wie Karl Franke formulierte.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ref">A contest "with a wink from the lovely Hiltrup family", as Karl Franke worded it.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ht">A contest "with a nod in the direction of the friendly Hiltrup family," as it was formulated by Karl Franke.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.mt">A contest "with a wink in the sympathetic Hiltruper family," as Karl Franke put it.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="5" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.sl">
    <source>Tatsächlich war es bald ein familiäres Miteinander bei Kaffee und Kuchen von den Ehrenamtlichen des Kulturbahnhofs.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ref">In fact, it soon became a familial togetherness with coffee and cake from the volunteers of the Kulturbahnhof.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ht">Actually, it would almost be like a family get together with coffee and cake provided by volunteers from the Kulturbahnhof.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.mt">In fact, it was soon a family get-together with coffee and cake from the volunteers of the Kulturbahnhof.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="6" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.sl">
    <source>Sieben Formationen traten an, von der Ein-Mann-Band bis zum großen Ensemble: Alvin Jasic mit Pianist Marcel Untied, Henk Humberg mit Gitarre, Rolf Ihmig, ein lange in Hiltrup lebender Albachtener, die Neun von den "Hiltruper Sternfarben", drei Mitglieder und drei Generationen der Familien Trenkamp und Claus, ein Ensemble aus dem Kindergarten Lummerland und schließlich Rike Weßling und die Zwarties.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ref">Seven acts performed, from a one-man band to the big ensemble: Alvin Jasic with pianist Marcel Untied, Henk Humberg with his guitar, Rolf Ihmig, an old-established Hiltrup man, the "Hiltruper Sternfarben", three members from three generations of the Trenkamp and Claus families, an ensemble from the kindergarten Lummerland and finally Rike Weßling und die Zwarties.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ht">Seven formation of musicians will perform, from a one-man band to a huge ensemble: Alvin Jasic with Pianist Marcel Untied, Henk Humberg with his guitar, longtime Hiltrup local Rolf Ihmig (originally from Albachten), the nine from the "Hiltrup Starcolors", 3 members and 3 generations of the Trenkamp and Claus family, an ensemble from the Lummerland Kindergarden and finally Rike Weßling and the Zwarties.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.mt">Seven groups competed, from the one-man band to the large ensemble: Alvin Jasic with pianist Marcel Untied, Henk Humberg with guitar, Rolf Ihmig, an Albachtener who lived for a long time in Hiltrup, the nine from the "Hiltruper Sternfarben," three members and three generations of the Trenkamp and Claus families, an ensemble from the kindergarten Lummerland and finally Rike Weßling and the Zwarties.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="7" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.sl">
    <source>Dieser Contest, so erklärte Bezirksbürgermeister Joachim Schmidt, sei eine Neuheit.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ref">This contest is a novelty, explains district mayor Joachim Schmidt.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ht">This contest, as district mayor Joachim Schmidt explained, should be a new feature.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.mt">This contest, declared district mayor Joachim Schmidt, is a novelty.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="8" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.sl">
    <source>Das haben wir in anderen Stadtteilen noch nicht erlebt.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ref">We have not seen something like this in other districts.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ht">We have never experienced such a thing in other neighborhoods.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.mt">We haven't seen that in other parts of the city.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="9" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.sl">
    <source>Womit sahen sich die Texter verbunden?</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ref">What did the songwriters sing about?</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ht">How are the lyricists connected to each other?</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.mt">What did the copywriters see themselves associated with?</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="10" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.sl">
    <source>Bei den Orten fanden der Hiltruper See und die Marktallee besonders häufig Erwähnung.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ref">Particularly popular places were the Hiltrup lake and Marktallee.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ht">Of all the locations, Lake Hiltruper and the Market Promenade are most often mentioned.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.mt">With the places the Hiltruper lake and the Marktallee were mentioned particularly frequently.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="11" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.sl">
    <source>Rolf Ihmig kürte die Allee in seinem schlagerartigen Lied zur "Kö von Hiltrup".</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ref">Rolf Ihmig dedicated the song to the avenue Marktalle in his folk-like song "Kö von Hiltrup".</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ht">Rolf Ihmig shortened the name of the promenade in his Schlager song "Kö von Hiltrup".</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.mt">Rolf Ihmig named the avenue "Kö von Hiltrup" in his hit-like song.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="12" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.sl">
    <source>Auch der Kulturbahnhof wurde gewürdigt.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ref">The Kulturbahnhof was also mentioned.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ht">Also the Kulturbahnhof was appreciated.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.mt">The Kulturbahnhof was also honoured.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="13" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.sl">
    <source>Immer wieder ging es um das Erleben von Miteinander an diesen Orten, besonders bei Alvin Jasic.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ref">Over and over again, the acts sang about experiencing togetherness in these places, especially Alvin Jasic.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ht">Again and again it had to do with the way people experienced each other at the various locations, particularly Alvin Jasic.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.mt">Again and again, it was about experiencing togetherness in these places, especially with Alvin Jasic.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="14" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.sl">
    <source>Karl Franke belebte die kurzen Umbaupausen mit Kurz-Interviews mit den Interpreten oder Hinweisen zu ihrem Schaffen.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ref">Karl Franke led the audience through the breaks with short interviews with the performers or some information about the artists.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ht">When they were changing from one band to the next, Karl Franke kept the short breaks lively by talking with the performers about their work.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.mt">Karl Franke animated the short breaks with short interviews with the performers or hints about their work.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="15" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.sl">
    <source>So erfuhr man von Humberg, dass er eigentlich Chemie studiert habe, jetzt aber auch Gitarre unterrichte.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ref">Thus, the audience learnt that Humberg that he had actually studied chemistry, but now also teaches guitar.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ht">That was how the audience found out about Humber and how he actually used to study chemistry, even though he now gives guitar lessons.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.mt">So it was learned from Humberg that he had actually studied chemistry, but now also teaches guitar.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="16" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.sl">
    <source>Vom Tontechniker Stefan Schemmelmann wusste Franke zu berichten, dass der jüngst in Ludwigshafen auftrat - auf einer großen Veranstaltung der BASF mit Barclay James Harvest im Programm.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ref">From the sound engineer Stefan Schemmelmann Franke reported that he had recently performed in Ludwigshafen - at a major BASF event with Barclay James Harvest as a main act.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ht">Franke could report that sound engineer Stefan Schemmelmann had most recently performed in Ludwigshafen on the program with Barclay James Harvest at a large BASF event.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.mt">Franke reported from the sound engineer Stefan Schemmelmann that he had recently performed in Ludwigshafen - at a major BASF event with Barclay James Harvest in the programme.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="17" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.sl">
    <source>Und Alvin Jasic hat unterdessen allerhand auf Youtube platziert.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ref">And Alvin Jasic has uploaded a lot of YouTube videos.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ht">Meanwhile Alvin Jasic posted multiple times on YouTube.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.mt">And Alvin Jasic, meanwhile, has put all sorts of things on YouTube.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="18" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.sl">
    <source>"Es geht nicht ums Gewinnen", hatte Franke gesagt.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ref">It’s not about winning, Franke had said.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ht">"It doesn't have to do with winning," said Franke.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.mt">"It's not about winning," Franke had said.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="19" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.sl">
    <source>Tatsächlich bekamen alle Teilnehmer ein Geschenk aus der Hiltruper Gastronomie.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ref">In fact, all participants received a gift from Hiltrup catering businesses.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ht">All participants actually received a gift from the Hiltrup gastronomy.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.mt">In fact, all participants received a gift from the Hiltruper catering trade.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="20" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.sl">
    <source>Für die Favoriten der Jury gab es dennoch etwas Besonderes - damit auch andere ihre Songs hören können.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ref">For the jury's favorites there was something special - so that others could also hear their songs.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ht">For the jury's favorites, there was still something special - that more people could also hear their music.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.mt">Still, there was something special for the judges "favorites - so that others could hear their songs, too.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="21" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.sl">
    <source>Eine ganze CD können Alvin Jasic und sein Pianist Marcel Untied mit Tontechniker Schemmelmann einspielen.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ref">Alvin Jasic and his pianist Marcel Untied can record an entire CD with sound technician Schemmelmann.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ht">Sound engineer Schemmelmann put on an entire CD by Alvin Jasic and his pianist Marcel Untied.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.mt">An entire CD can be recorded by Alvin Jasic and his pianist Marcel Untied with sound engineer Schemmelmann.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="22" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.sl">
    <source>Weitere Musiker können ein Lied aufnehmen: Ihmig mit seinem Hiltrup-Schlager, der Franke besonders mit seiner Musikalität beeindruckte, und das "Lummerland-Rudel": "ein sehr schöner Auftritt" mit zehn Kindern und zwei Erzieherinnen an Gitarre und Cajon, Laura Kastner und Lina Tölle.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ref">Other musicians can record a song: Ihmig with his Hiltrup hit, which especially impressed Franke with his musicality, and the “Lummerland pack:” “a very good performance” with ten children and two teachers on guitar and cajón, Laura Kastner and Lina Tölle.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ht">Various additional musicians recorded a song: Ihmig with his Hiltrup Schlager, whose musicality particularly impressed Franke, as well the "Lummerland-Rudel": "a very beautiful performance" with ten children and their two teachers, Laura Kastner and Lina Tölle, playing guitar and cajon.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.mt">Other musicians can record a song: Ihmig with his Hiltrup hit, which particularly impressed Franke with its musicality, and the "Lummerland pack": "a very nice performance" with ten children and two kindergarten teachers on guitar and cajon, Laura Kastner and Lina Tölle.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="23" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.sl">
    <source>Wie alle traten auch die Kinder zum Finale noch einmal auf - und klangen sogar ohne elektronische Unterstützung "richtig gut", wie Franke sagte.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ref">Like everyone else, the children also performed again for the finals - and even without electronic support, they sounded "really good," Franke said.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ht">Like all of the others, the children performed one last time in the finale - even without electronic accompaniment, they sounded, "really good", according to Franke.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.mt">Like everyone else, the children performed again for the finale - and even without electronic support, they sounded "really good," as Franke said.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="24" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.sl">
    <source>Leiten ließ sich die Jury von den Aspekten Originalität, Bezug zu Hiltrup, Eingängigkeit der Melodie und Wiedererkennungswert.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ref">The jury was guided by the aspects of originality, reference to Hiltrup, catchiness of the melody and recognition value.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ht">The jury judged performers on aspects of originality, their connection to Hiltrup, as well as how catchy and memorable their melodies were.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.mt">The jury was guided by the aspects of originality, reference to Hiltrup, catchiness of the melody and recognition value.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="25" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.sl">
    <source>Der Jury gehörten Gisbert Keller von der Westfälischen Schule für Musik, Andreas Klomfaß vom KvG-Gymnasium und Oliver Ahlers vom Wirtschaftsverbund sowie Jan Kaven, Vorsitzender der Stadtteiloffensive, an.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ref">The jury included Gisbert Keller from the Westphalian School of Music, Andreas Klomfaß from KvG-Gymnasium and Oliver Ahlers from the Trade Association as well as Jan Kaven, chairman of the district offensive.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ht">On the jury sat the Westphalian Music School's Gisbert Keller, the KvG Gymnasium's Andreas Klomfaß and the trade association's Oliver Ahlers, as well as head of the neighborhood campaign's Jan Kaven.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.mt">The jury consisted of Gisbert Keller from the Westphalian School of Music, Andreas Klomfaß from the KvG-Gymnasium and Oliver Ahlers from the Wirtschaftsverbund, as well as Jan Kaven, chairman of the district offensive.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="26" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.sl">
    <source>Die Stadtteiloffensive hatte das Ereignis aus Anlass ihres zehnjährigen Bestehens ins Leben gerufen.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ref">The district offensive launched the event on the occasion of its ten-year anniversary.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ht">The neighborhood campaign used the even to mark the occasion of the ten year founding of the organization.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.mt">The district offensive had brought the event to life on the occasion of its ten-year anniversary.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="27" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.sl">
    <source>Sie wertete das Event als vollen Erfolg.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ref">They considered the event a complete success.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ht">They saw the event as a complete success.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.mt">She rated the event as a complete success.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="28" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.sl">
    <source>Alle seien "sehr zufrieden", und "die Atmosphäre war gut" im bald sehr vollen Kulturbahnhof.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ref">Everyone was "very satisfied," and "the atmosphere was good" in the very crowded Kulturbahnhof.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.ht">Everyone was "very satisfied" and "the atmosphere was good" in the nearly full Kulturbahnhof.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_016_wn.de.531144.mt">Everyone was "very satisfied," and "the atmosphere was good" in the soon-to-be very crowded Kulturbahnhof.</translation>
  </seg>
</set>
