<set id="w19_deen" source-language="de" target-language="en">
  <seg id="1" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.sl">
    <source>Audi: "Dieselgate"-Aufarbeitung dauert länger als geplant</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.ref">Audi: "Dieselgate" regeneration takes longer than planned</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.ht">Audi: "Dieselgate" refurbishment taking longer than planned</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.mt">Audi: "Dieselgate" refurbishment takes longer than planned</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="2" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.sl">
    <source>"Die Diesel-Taskforce gibt es immer noch", sagte Entwicklungsvorstand Peter Mertens dem Branchenblatt "Automobilwoche".</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.ref">There is still a diesel taskforce, said Peter Mertens, chief development officer from the ‘Automobilwoche’ trade journal.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.ht">"The diesel task force is still at work", said Chief Development Officer Peter Mertens to industry publication  "Automobilwoche".</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.mt">"The diesel task force still exists," Chief Development Officer Peter Mertens told the industry publication "Automobilwoche."</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="3" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.sl">
    <source>Der inhaftierte und beurlaubte Audi-Chef Rupert Stadler hatte im Dezember 2017 angekündigt, die Taskforce werde bald aufgelöst.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.ref">In December 2017 the imprisoned and suspended Audi CEO Rupert Stadler had announced, the taskforce will be dissolved soon.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.ht">Audi chief Rupert Stadler, who has been detained and is currently suspended, had announced in December 2017 that the task force would soon be dissolved.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.mt">Audi CEO Rupert Stadler, who was arrested and placed on leave, announced in December 2017 that the task force would soon be disbanded.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="4" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.sl">
    <source>"Im ersten Quartal 2018 sind voraussichtlich alle Motor/Getriebe-Kombinationen geprüft", hatte er damals gesagt.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.ref">In the first quarter of 2018 all engine/transmission combinations will have been checked, he said at the time.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.ht">"We expect all engine/gear combinations to have been checked by the first quarter of 2018", he said at the time.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.mt">"All engine / transmission combinations are expected to be tested in the first quarter of 2018," he said at the time.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="5" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.sl">
    <source>Mertens sagte nun: "Anfang Juli haben wir ein wichtiges Etappenziel in der Aufarbeitung der Dieselkrise erreicht.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.ref">Mertens now says: ‘At the start of July we have an important milestone by which the diesel crisis will have been worked out.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.ht">Mertens now says: "At the start of July, we reached an important landmark in dealing with the diesel crisis.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.mt">Mertens said: "At the beginning of July, we reached an important milestone in dealing with the diesel crisis.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="6" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.sl">
    <source>Wir haben die internen technischen Analysen unserer VTDI-Motoren abgeschlossen.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.ref">We have completed the internal technical analyses of our VTDI engines.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.ht">We have completed the internal technical analyses of our VTDI engines.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.mt">We have completed the internal technical analyses of our VTDI engines.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="7" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.sl">
    <source>Die Taskforce war im September 2015 nach der Entdeckung des Dieselskandals bei der Audi-Mutter Volkswagen gegründet worden.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.ref">The taskforce was set up in September 2015 following the discovery at Audi parent company Volkswagen.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.ht">The task force was set up in September 2015 after the outbreak of the diesel scandal at Audi's parent company, Volkswagen.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.mt">The task force was set up in September 2015 following the discovery of the diesel scandal at Audi's parent company Volkswagen.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="8" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.sl">
    <source>Mertens betonte, der Autobauer habe "gravierende organisatorische Änderungen" vorgenommen, damit ein solcher Skandal nie wieder vorkomme.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.ref">Mertens highlighted that the automobile manufacturers had made ‘serious, organizational changes’, to prevent such a scandal ever happening again.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.ht">Mertens stressed that the car manufacturer had made "drastic organizational changes" to prevent another such scandal from occurring.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.mt">Mertens stressed that the carmaker had made "serious organisational changes" to ensure such a scandal would never happen again.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="9" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.sl">
    <source>Der VW-Aufsichtsrat hatte am Freitag eine Entscheidung über Stadlers Zukunft vertagt und will an diesem Dienstag weiter diskutieren.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.ref">The VW Supervisory Board had postponed a decision on Stadler's future on Friday and will continue this discussion on Tuesday.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.ht">The VW supervisory board deferred a decision on Stadler's future on Friday and will hold further discussions on Tuesday.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.mt">The VW supervisory board postponed a decision on Stadler's future on Friday and plans to discuss it further on Tuesday.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="10" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.sl">
    <source>Die Ermittlungsbehörden werfen dem Audi-Chef vor, nach Bekanntwerden der Abgasbetrügereien den Verkauf von Dieselautos mit falschen Abgaswerten zugelassen zu haben.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.ref">The investigating authorities accuse the Audi boss, following awareness of exhaust emission cheating, of permitting the sale of diesel automobiles with false emission values.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.ht">The investigatory authority accuses the Audi chief of having approved the sale of diesel vehicles with falsified emissions ratings after becoming aware of emissions fraud.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.mt">The investigating authorities accuse the Audi boss of having allowed the sale of diesel cars with incorrect exhaust emission values after becoming aware of the emissions cheating.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="11" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.sl">
    <source>Dabei habe er von den Manipulationen gewusst oder sie bewusst ignoriert.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.ref">He must have known about the tampering or deliberately ignored it.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.ht">They accuse him of having known of, or ignored, the manipulation.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.mt">In doing so, he allegedly knew about the manipulations or deliberately ignored them.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="12" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.sl">
    <source>Derzeit leitet Vertriebsvorstand Bram Schot das Unternehmen als kommissarischer Vorstandschef.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.ref">Currently the Sales Director Bram Schot heads the company as Acting Chief Executive Officer.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.ht">Sales director Bram Schot is currently managing the company as interim chief executive.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.mt">Currently, Chief Sales Officer Bram Schot heads the company as acting CEO.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="13" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.sl">
    <source>Wegen der Umstellung auf den neuen Abgas- und Verbrauchsprüfstandard WLTP gebe es Produktionsausfälle bei Audi, sagte Schot der "Heilbronner Stimme".</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.ref">After conversion to the new emissions and consumption standard WLTP, there were production losses at Audi, Schot told the ‘Heilbronner Stimme’.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.ht">Schot told the "Heilbronner Stimme" that the conversion to the new WLTP exhaust and consumption testing standard would result in production losses at Audi.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.mt">Due to the changeover to the new exhaust and fuel consumption test standard WLTP, there are production losses at Audi, Schot told the "Heilbronner Stimme."</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="14" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.sl">
    <source>Grundsätzlich sehe er eine sinkende Nachfrage nach Limousinen wie den Audimodellen A6, A7 und A8, die in Neckarsulm produziert werden.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.ref">Essentially, he sees a falling demand for limousines such as the Audi models A6, A7 and A8, produced in Neckarsulm.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.ht">He sees a falling demand for limousine models, such as Audi models A6, A7 and A8, which are produced  in Neckarsulm.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.mt">In principle, he sees a decreasing demand for saloons such as the A6, A7 and A8 audio models, which are produced in Neckarsulm.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="15" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.sl">
    <source>"Das Segment an sich ist schwierig", sagte er.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.ref">The segment in itself is a difficult one, he said.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.ht">"The sector is a difficult one in its own right", he said.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.mt">"The segment itself is difficult," he said.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="16" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.sl">
    <source>Schot setzt auf Elektromobilität.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.ref">Schot is for electromobility.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.ht">Schot is focusing on electromobility.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.mt">Schot focuses on electric mobility.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="17" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.sl">
    <source>Für den e-tron, das erste Audi-Elektroauto, lägen bereits 15.000 Reservierungen vor.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.ref">There are already 15,000 reservations for the e-tron, the first Audi electric automobile.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.ht">15,000 reservations have already been made for the e-tron, Audi's first electric vehicle.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_007_nw-news.de.115733.mt">There have already been 15,000 reservations for the e-tron, the first Audi electric car.</translation>
  </seg>
</set>
