<set id="w19_deen" source-language="de" target-language="en">
  <seg id="1" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.sl">
    <source>Treysa hat mit Vandalismus und Unrat zu kämpfen</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ref">Treysa has struggled against vandalism and garbage</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ht">Treysa marred by vandalism and trash</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.mt">Treysa has to deal with vandalism and debris</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="2" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.sl">
    <source>Der Einstieg in den 36 Kilometer langen Bahnradweg im Rotkäppchenland in Treysa präsentiert sich schwer auffindbar und vermüllt.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ref">Accessing the 36-kilometer cycle track in Rotkäppchenland in Treysa is very difficult and heavily littered.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ht">The start of the 36 kilometer-long track cycling path in the Red Riding Hood Forest in Treysa is difficult to find and littered.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.mt">The entrance to the 36-kilometre-long railway cycle path in Red Riding Hood Land in Treysa is difficult to find and littered.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="3" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.sl">
    <source>Rezepte gegen den grassierenden Vandalismus werden gesucht, aber Lösungen zeichnen sich kaum ab.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ref">Attempts are made to remedy the rampant vandalism, but there are hardly any signs of solutions.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ht">Solutions to the rampant vandalism are being sought, but nothing concrete stands out as of yet.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.mt">Recipes against rampant vandalism are sought, but solutions are few and far between.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="4" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.sl">
    <source>Scherben, Zigarettenkippen, Müll und Unrat, demolierte Mülleimer und mittlerweile demontierte Hinweisschilder - so präsentiert sich seit Längerem der Einstieg mit Sitzgruppe zum Radweg auf dem Haaße-Hügel in Treysa.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ref">Shards, cigarette butts, garbage and rubbish, demolished rubbish bins and now dismantled signs - so for quite some time presents itself the entrance with seating area to the bike path on the Haaße-hill in Treysa.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ht">Shards of glass, cigarette butts, litter and trash, broken bins and discarded notice signs - for a long time, this has been the scene at the starting point of the bike path and its seating area on the Haaße hill in Treysa.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.mt">Shards, cigarette butts, garbage and debris, demolished bins and meanwhile dismantled signs - this is how the entrance with seating group to the bike path on the Haaße hill in Treysa has been presented for a long time.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="5" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.sl">
    <source>Für das Vorzeigeobjekt Bahnradweg im Rotkäppchenland ein mehr als unrühmlicher Anblick.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ref">The sight of the bicycle path, which is the flagship object in Rotkäpchenland, is more than inglorious.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ht">For the showpiece bike path in Red Riding Hood Land - it is more than an inglorious sight.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.mt">For the showpiece railway cycle path in the Red Riding Hood country a more than inglorious sight.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="6" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.sl">
    <source>Das Thema beschäftigt Mitglieder der ADFC-Ortsgruppe Schwalmstadt aber auch andere schon länger, so der Radverkehrsbeauftragte der Stadt Ulrich Wüstenhagen.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ref">The matter is of concern to the ADFC (German Cyclists Association) chapter Schwalmstadt, but others have also taken interest for some time, according to the city's cycling commissioner Ulrich Wüstenhagen.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ht">The local section of the German Bicycle Club (ADFC) in Schwalmstadt has been dealing with the issue for much longer, according to the city's cycling officer, Ulrich Wüstenhagen.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.mt">The topic has been occupying members of the ADFC local group Schwalmstadt but also others for some time, according to Ulrich Wüstenhagen, the city's cycling commissioner.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="7" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.sl">
    <source>Das Problem sei bereits im Radverkehrsbeirat angesprochen worden.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ref">The problem has already been addressed by the bicycle traffic advisory body.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ht">The issue has already been discussed in the cycling advisory board.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.mt">The issue had already been raised in the Cycling Advisory Board.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="8" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.sl">
    <source>Eine Lösung gebe es bisher nicht.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ref">There is no solution so far.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ht">No solution has yet been found.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.mt">So far, there is no solution.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="9" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.sl">
    <source>Die Vorschläge reichten von der Verlegung der Sitzgruppe bis hin zu regelmäßiger Entleerung der Abfallbehälter und Reinigung der Flächen an der Einstiegsstelle.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ref">Suggestions ranged from transferring the seating area to the regular emptying of garbage cans, and cleaning the point of entry areas.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ht">Suggestions ranged from the removal of the seating area to the regular emptying of waste bins and the cleaning of the area at the start of the ascent.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.mt">The proposals ranged from the relocation of the seating group to the regular emptying of the waste bins and cleaning of the areas at the entry point.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="10" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.sl">
    <source>"Ich denke, Letzteres wäre das Gebot der Stunde - unabhängig von möglichen weiteren Aktivitäten", sagt Wüstenhagen.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ref">I think, the latter would be the order of the day, irrespective of any further activities, says Wüstenhagen.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ht">"I think that the time has come for the latter - regardless of any further action that may be taken", said Wüstenhagen.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.mt">"I think the latter would be the order of the day - regardless of possible further activities," Wüstenhagen says.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="11" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.sl">
    <source>Guido Hahn (ADFC) berichtet, das Thema ebenfalls in den Ortsbeirat eingebracht zu haben.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ref">Guido Hahn (ADFC) says he also brought the issue up with the local advisory council.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ht">Guido Hahn (ADFC) states that he has also raised the issue in the local advisory board.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.mt">Guido Hahn (ADFC) reports that he has also brought the topic to the local advisory board.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="12" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.sl">
    <source>Nicht nur der Müll treibt Radfahrer und Anwohner um - die Sitzgruppe ist an Wochenenden regelmäßiger Treffpunkt zum Feiern.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ref">Not only the rubbish is a nuisance for cyclists and residents - on weekends the seating group is a regular meeting place for partying.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ht">It is not just rubbish which is a concern for cyclists and residents - the seating area is a regular meeting spot for youths at the weekend.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.mt">It's not just the rubbish that drives cyclists and residents around - the seating area is a regular meeting place for partying at weekends.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="13" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.sl">
    <source>Dabei geht es nicht nur häufig laut zu, bei den Gelagen wird auch zerstört: Pfosten aus der Erde gerissen, Mülleimer demoliert, Schilder umgeknickt, Sitzmöbel beschmiert.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ref">It is not just about the noise, there are also disturbances due to parties: Posts pulled out of the ground, garbage cans wrecked, signs snapped and seating daubed.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ht">These youths are not only loud, they also cause damage: posts are ripped out of the ground, rubbish bins are broken, signs are bent and seats are daubed with dirt.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.mt">Not only is it often loud, the banquets also destroy: posts are torn out of the ground, rubbish bins are demolished, signs are bent over, seating furniture is smeared.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="14" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.sl">
    <source>Freiwillige hätten bereits häufiger aufgeräumt, erzählt ADFC-Mitglied Susanne Klippert.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ref">Frequently volunteers have already cleaned up, explains the ADFC member Susanne Klippert.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ht">ADFC member Susanne Klippert claims that volunteers have frequently cleaned up.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.mt">Volunteers have already cleaned up more often, says ADFC member Susanne Klippert.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="15" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.sl">
    <source>Die Aktionen seien aber nur der sprichwörtliche Tropfen auf den heißen Stein.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ref">Actions are only proverbial drops in the ocean.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ht">These actions, however, are just the proverbial drop in the ocean.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.mt">But the actions are only the proverbial drop in the ocean.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="16" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.sl">
    <source>Sie ärgern sich, dass der Rastplatz am Radweg in Treysa Treffpunkt für Saufgelage ist.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ref">They are annoyed that the rest area at the cycle track in Treysa is a meeting point for binge-drinking.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ht">People are angry that the resting area of the Treysa bike path has become a meeting point for drunkards.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.mt">They are annoyed that the rest area on the bike path in Treysa is a meeting point for binge drinking.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="17" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.sl">
    <source>"Entlang des gesamten Radweges liegt hier am Haaße-Hügel eindeutig der Schwerpunkt", bestätigt der Radverkehrsbeauftragte, der sich nun auch um die neue Radstätte in Ziegenhain sorgt, die heute eröffnet wird.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ref">Clearly the focus point along the entire bike path is here on the Haaße, confirms the cycling commissioner, who now is also responsible for the cycling site in Ziegenhain, which will be opened today.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ht">"This point of the Haaße hill is the focal point of the entire bike path", confirms the cycling officer, who is currently occupied with the new water wheel in Ziegenhain which is being declared open today.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.mt">"Along the entire cycle path, the focus is clearly on the Haaße hill," confirms the cycling commissioner, who is now also concerned about the new cycling centre in Ziegenhain, which will be opened today.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="18" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.sl">
    <source>"Erleidet sie dasselbe Schicksal, wird es richtig teuer".</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ref">If it suffers the same fate, it will cost dearly.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ht">"If the bike path suffers the same fate - the price will be high".</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.mt">'If she suffers the same fate, it's going to be really expensive. '</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="19" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.sl">
    <source>Eine weitere Idee sei eine Videoüberwachung am Hügel: "Möglicherweise setzt das die Schwelle deutlich höher, sich an Gemeingut zu vergreifen.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ref">Another idea is placing video surveillance on the hill: "Possibly this raises the threshold to engage in damaging common property.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ht">One other idea is the video surveillance of the hill: "Maybe this will raise the stakes of misbehavior on public property.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.mt">Another idea, he said, is video surveillance on the hill: "Maybe that sets the threshold much higher for seizing public property.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="20" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.sl">
    <source>Das würde allerdings voraussetzen, dass dann zeitnah eine Polizeistreife vorbeikommt.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ref">However, this would require a police patrol to come out.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ht">However, this would then need a police patrol to come promptly.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.mt">This would, however, require a police patrol to pass by in a timely manner.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="21" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.sl">
    <source>Grundsätzlich wünscht sich Wüstenhagen eine Entwicklung des Haaße-Hügels.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ref">In principle, Wüstenhagen supports the development of the Haaße hill.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ht">Wüstenhagen wants to develop the Haaße hill.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.mt">In principle, Wüstenhagen wishes to see the development of the Haaße Hill.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="22" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.sl">
    <source>Er müsse attraktiver gestaltet werden.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ref">It needs to be made more attractive.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ht">It has to be made more appealing.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.mt">It needs to be made more attractive.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="23" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.sl">
    <source>Mit der Frequentierung des Radweges bisher könne man nämlich sehr zufrieden sein.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ref">So far one can be very satisfied with how well the bicycle path is frequented.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ht">Up to now, the use of the bike path has been very pleasing.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.mt">One can be very satisfied with the frequency of the cycle path so far.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="24" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.sl">
    <source>Die touristische Vermarktung ist noch ausbaufähig.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ref">It is still possible to develop tourism-related marketing.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ht">Tourist marketing has potential for development.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.mt">The tourism marketing is still expandable.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="25" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.sl">
    <source>Unser Radweg ist im Vergleich zu anderen in Deutschland sehr hochwertig", so die ADFC-Mitglieder.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ref">Our cycle track is of very high quality compared to others in German’, agreed the ADFC members.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ht">Compared to others in Germany, our bike path is really good" according to the ADFC members.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.mt">Our bike path is of a very high quality compared to others in Germany, "says the ADFC members.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="26" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.sl">
    <source>Als äußerst kritische Gefahrenstelle schätzt ADFC-Mitglied Susanne Klippert die Situation in der Ascheröder Straße in Treysa ein.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ref">ADFC member Susanne Klippert considers the situation in the Ascheröder Strasse in Treysa to be critically dangerous.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ht">ADFC Susanne Klippert believes that situation on Ascheröder Straße in Treysa as very dangerous.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.mt">ADFC member Susanne Klippert considers the situation in the Ascheröder Strasse in Treysa to be an extremely critical danger point.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="27" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.sl">
    <source>Es gibt keine Abbiegespur auf den Haaße-Hügel.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ref">There is no turning lane on Haaße Hügel.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ht">There is no turning lane on the Haaße hill.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.mt">There is no turning track on the Haaße hill.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="28" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.sl">
    <source>Bei regem Verkehr kann es passieren, dass Radfahrer mitten auf der Straße zwischen beidseitigem Verkehrsfluss warten müssen", erläutert sie.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ref">In heavy traffic, cyclists may end up waiting in the middle of bidirectional traffic flows", she explains.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ht">When traffic is busy, it can be the case that cyclists have to wait in the middle of the road between two lanes of traffic", she explains.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.mt">In heavy traffic it can happen that cyclists have to wait in the middle of the road between traffic on both sides, "she explains.</translation>
  </seg>
  <seg id="29" doc-id="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.sl">
    <source>Das sei für sportliche Fahrer kein Problem, wohl aber für Ältere und besonders für Kinder.</source>
    <reference>NA</reference>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ref">That would not be a problem for sporty cyclists, but is for older people and especially for children.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.ht">For sporty riders, this is no problem, but it is a different matter altogether for the elderly and particularly for children.</translation>
    <translation system="../data/appraise_import/deen_015_hna.de.183709.mt">This is not a problem for sporty drivers, but probably for older people and especially for children.</translation>
  </seg>
</set>
